Is it that easy to adjust the Uka-no-Mitama virus?
ウカノミタマ·ウイルスの調整ってのは
そう簡単にできるもんなのかね
The process itself should be pretty much automated,
作業工程自体は ほぼ全自動のはずですからね
so as long as the equipment still works, yes.
機材さえ生きていれば
They chose Uka-no-Mitama precisely because of how easy it is to update.
そもそも アップデートの容易さがウカノミタマの利点ですし…
To think that a benign virus would
end up becoming an actual disease...
善玉ウイルスが本物の病原菌に化けるとはな
We thought of it as an iron shield defending our food autonomy,
食料自給を守る鉄の壁かと思っていたら
but it ended up being a double-edged sword.
実は諸刃の剣だったわけだ
Go.
出してくれ
"Jesus told them another parable:
「イエスは別の例えを持ち出して言われた」
'The kingdom of heaven is like
a man who sowed good seed in his field.
「天の国は次のように例えられる ある人が良い種を畑に播いた」
But while everyone was sleeping,
「人々が眠っている間に敵が来て
his enemy came and sowed weeds among the wheat, and went away."
麦の中に毒麦を播いて行った」
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
#21: Blood-Stained Reward
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒 ASUKA    校对:西西    时间轴:葛蔓     压制：娜夏
The security is still active...
セキュリティーは生きてる
Where can I find another way in...?
他に入れそうな場所は…
Oh?
Dammit! What a huge place...
くそ…何て広さだ
Well, this factory centrally manages the defense
virus in order to distribute it to the entire Hokuriku area.
北陸全域に配給するための防御ウイルスを
一括管理している工場ですからね
It's amazing that such a large-scale facility can
continue to operate in a fully automated manner.
これだけの規模の設備が完全無人化されたまま稼働してるなんてな…
The bigger the prey, the easier it is to target.
図体が大きい獲物ほど狙いやすい
Especially when you're wielding a
poisoned needle strong enough to kill a whale.
鯨も殺すほどの毒針を使うとなれば　なおさら…
This sort of tactic is just like Makishima.
槙島らしい戦術ですよ
It's probably from Kougami.
多分狡噛さんです
He must have seen us land.
私たちが着陸するのが見えたんでしょう
In which case, he's nearby.
彼もすぐ近くにいます
Tsunemori speaking.
I didn't expect you to get here so soon.
常守です
思いの外早いお出ましだったな
Don't underestimate the Bureau's resources.
公安局を舐めないでください
You're not the only one here
capable of driving Makishima into a corner.
あなただけが槙島を追い詰められるわけじゃありません
He's already inside the facility.
やつはもう　施設内に入ってる
In fact, he's probably adjusting the Uka-no-Mitama
virus right now using the equipment Kudama left in the lab.
おそらく　管巻がラボに残していった機材を使い
ウカノミタマの調整に取り掛かっているはずだ
Or he might even have finished already.
あるいは もう終わらせているかも…
We're not going to let him have his way.
あの男の思いどおりにはさせません
Then we don't have a moment to lose.
だとしたら時間がない
We have to shut down the entire facility before he's
able to distribute the Uka-no-Mitama that he tampered with.
やつが弄ったウカノミタマを撒き散らす前に
ここの施設そのものを停止させるしかない
The Bureau has the authority to cut off the power to this facility, right?
公安局の権限でこの施設への電力供給を遮断できるはずだな
That would halt not only its operation but its security system as well.
その場合 センターの機能だけでなく
セキュリティーシステムも全滅です
That's what you want, isn't it?
あなたの狙いはそれですね
You're trying to use us to lift the security so that
you can beat us to Makishima and kill him, aren't you?
私たちを利用して セキュリティーを解除させ
先回りして槙島を殺すつもりでしょう
We can't let you do that.
やらせませんよ　絶対に…
Makishima is trying to destroy this country.
槙島はこの国を潰す気でいる
The Bureau has only one choice right now.
今公安局が選べる選択肢は一つだけだ
Cut the power.
電力を止めろ
Then this country will be saved.
それでこの国が救われる
I will save you too.
私はあなたも救います
I will not let Kougami Shinya become a murderer.
狡噛慎也を殺人犯にはさせません
Then let the fastest one win.
なら早い者勝ちだな
Can't we have control of the security system
transferred to us from the Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry?
この施設 セキュリティーシステムの権限だけ
農林省から委譲してもらうわけにはいかないんですか
The process will take time.
手続きに時間を食う
If Makishima finishes before us, it's checkmate.
その隙に槙島が王手をかけるかもしれん
We have no choice but to stop the facility itself, like Kougami said.
ここは狡噛の言うとおり
施設そのものを停止させるしか手はない
Kunizuka?
六合塚
I've already disabled the secondary power supply.
予備電源への切り替えコマンドは凍結済みです
All we have to do now is cut off the primary power source.
後は発電所からの送電を止めるだけ
There's something I'd like to ask of you.
一つ確認させてください
When you encounter Kougami, if the Eliminator ends
up activating because his Crime Coefficient is over 300,
もし狡噛さんと遭遇した時 犯罪係数が３００を超えて
エリミネーターが起動するようなら
please don't shoot him. Call me.
発砲を控えて私を呼んでください
What's the point of that?
君を呼んでどうなる
I've got a trump card up my sleeve for Kougami.
狡噛さん相手には切り札があります
Don't worry. Just leave it to me.
大丈夫　任せてください
Now we'll go after Makishima.
私たちはこれから槙島聖護を追う
You'll help us, right?
協力してくれるわよね
Of course.
Then I need you to lock this gun
in Paralyzer mode with the safety off.
「無論です」
ならこの銃 セーフティーを解除したまま
機能をパラライザーに固定して
You can do that, right?
できるでしょ
The Dominator decides its enforcement
mode based on the measured Crime Coefficients.
「ドミネーターは計測した犯罪係数に基づいて
執行モードが決定されます」
This is the foundation of the system that
maintains public safety. It cannot be changed.
「これは 現在の治安維持の根幹であり
不可侵のシステムです」
If we are to fight Makishima, we need weapons that can do the job.
槙島に立ち向かうには それ相応の強力な武器がいる
We have to protect ourselves too, after all.
私たちだって自分の身は守らなきゃならない
If we can't use the Dominators, we'll have no
choice but to depend on more primitive weapons.
もしドミネーターが使えないなら
より原始的な武器に頼るしかなくなるわ
If worst comes to worst, we may end
up killing Makishima with those weapons.
最悪の場合…
それで槙島を殺す羽目になるかもしれない
Your lack of resourcefulness
would be at fault in that scenario, not us.
「それはあなた方の 自助努力の欠落によるものです」
Our abilities are limited and the probability that we will
capture Makishima alive without problems is hardly 100%.
私たちの能力には限界があるし
槙島を無事確保できる確率は １００％には及ばないわ
If you're able to grant an exception here,
ここであなたたちが一つ特例を認めれば
we may be able to improve that chance a little.
その確率を少し改善できる
Think about which course of action offers the most benefit.
何が最善の判断か
考えてみなさいよ
You're good at calculating risk and reward, right?
損得勘定は得意でしょ
From now until Makishima Shougo is captured,
「現時点より 槙島聖護捕獲の達成に至るまで
we will grant an exception on the applicable terminal device.
該当する端末装置の特例を許可します」
The safety will remain off.
「セーフティー　常時解除」
Mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
「モード ノンリーサル·パラライザー」
However, please pay close attention to how you
use it to ensure the other detectives do not find out.
「ただし 他の捜査官には露見しないよう
運用には 細心の注意を払ってください」
I know.
分かってるわ
Say, young lady.
おい　お嬢ちゃん…
You've been acting strange ever since the Chief called you out.
局長に呼び出されてから こっちちょっと変だぞ
I don't know what happened, but are you sure you can shoulder that burden alone?
何があったのか知らないが
何もかもしょい込み過ぎじゃないのか
Are you worried about me?
心配ですか
Yeah, you're acting the same as Kougami did.
ああ　狡噛の時と一緒だ
I don't wanna see you push yourself
too hard as an Inspector and burn out.
突っ走り過ぎた監視官の末路なんて
俺はそう何度も見たかない
Then would you like to check my Crime Coefficient?
それなら 私の犯罪係数確かめてみます
Hey, hey...
おいおい…
It's okay. Please point the Dominator at me.
構いません
ドミネーターを向けてみてください
I'll delete the record using my authority as an Inspector.
記録は監視官権限で削除しますから
Crime Coefficient is 24.
「犯罪係数　２４」
An Inspector registered at the Criminal Investigation Department.
「刑事課 登録監視官」
See?
Right now, I'm someone the System wants.
ねっ　今の私はシステムの望みどおりの人間なんですよ
Yeah...
Kunizuka, please go ahead.
じゃあ六合塚さん　お願いします
Okay. I'll cut off the power to the entire facility.
了解
施設全域への送電をカットします
Not bad, Bureau.
やってくれるな　公安局…
Here goes!
よし
Either way, Makishima's attempt at bio-terrorism ends here.
ともかく槙島のバイオテロはこれで完全に失敗だ
Wouldn't the rational thing be to escape immediately?
冷静な判断力があれば すぐさま逃げ出す算段を打つんじゃないか
I'm not so sure about that.
そうでしょうか
True, Makishima has carefully considered his actions up to this point,
槙島のこれまでの行動は確かに周到でしたけど
but that doesn't necessarily mean he acts purely on logic.
損得勘定だけでは割り切れなかった気がします
Are you saying that he'll stick to his plan even now?
この期に及んで あいつがまだ粘ると
If there's any way he can succeed, yes.
手があるとすれば…非常電源
What about the emergency power supply?
Right now, we're just blocking his use of it from outside, aren't we?
今はまだ 外部からのコマンドで切り替えを遮断してるだけですよね
Yeah.
That means it can still be manually
rebooted via the control board inside the facility.
ええ
だったら　施設内の制御盤から手動で再起動をかければいい
That's his only chance for getting the power back.
もう一度電力を取り戻すチャンスはそこしかない
Should we wait for him at the central control room, then?
中央管制室か…
網を張るか
Wait.
We can't rule out the possibility that he'll simply try to escape.
待て
素直に逃げ出す公算だってじゅうぶんにある
There's no time for us to make a detour.
寄り道はしていられないぞ
Let's split in two.
二手に分かれましょう
I'll go to the control room.
私は管制室に
Inspector Ginoza, please check the university's lab.
宜野座さんは大学のラボを当たってください
I'll go with Inspector Tsunemori.
私は常守監視官に同伴します
If we work with Shion at Headquarters via the main security console,
警備責任者のコンソールから本部の志恩と連携すれば
we might be able to get access to the security cameras here.
せめて施設の監視カメラぐらいは こちらでも制御できるかも
Then we'll be in charge of chasing him down, huh?
となると　追いかけっこは俺たちのコンビだな
Come on, don't make that face.
そう嫌そうな顔をするな
It's our job as men to take on the dirty work.
荒事は男が引き受けるもんさ
Dammit!
くそっ
Did something happen at the Ministry of Welfare?
厚生省で　何かあったんですか
Does it seem that way?
そんなふうに見えますか
You look like you could take on the
world right now, but at the same time,
今のあなたは誰よりも前向きなのに
you look like that whole world's weighing on your shoulders.
誰よりも落ち込んでいるふうに見えます
Giving up here wouldn't resolve anything.
立ち止まっていても何一つ解決しない
I just have to press forward.
今はただ進むしかない
No matter how small it may be, there's still hope.
どんなに小さくても希望はある
As long as I don't give up on it,
それを諦めないかぎり
I can continue to be a detective until the end.
私は最後まで刑事のままでいられる
When you joined us as a new Inspector,
新しい監視官がやって来たとき
my first impression was that you were a naïve
little girl who couldn't possibly be fit for the job.
最初は甘そうなお嬢ちゃんだと思いました
こんな仕事はとうてい勤まらないって
Yeah, I guess I was.
うん　そうだったかも…
But in fact, I've never been further from the truth.
でも　あのときの印象は完全に間違っていた
I'm sure of that now.
今ならそう断言できる
I'd trust you with my life, Inspector Tsunemori.
あなたになら命を預けられます　常守さん
You think too highly of me.
買いかぶり過ぎですよ
Clear.
クリア
I guess we made it in time...
間に合った…のかな
But do you think Makishima will really come this way?
でも　ここにホントに槙島が？
That's right... Why isn't there anyone here?
そうか…誰もいないなんて変だ
What?
There's someone who can foresee
Makishima's actions more accurately than me.
えっ
彼なら私よりも正確に槙島の動きを予測する
If we were right, I'd expect to see Kougami here already.
これが正解だったなら
狡噛さんが先回りしてなきゃおかしいわ
Why...?
どうして…
There must be something we're overlooking.
何か見落としてる気がする
There's something I need to ask you.
一つ 確かめておかなきゃならない
Here and now? What's on your mind?
こんなときに どうした
You helped Kougami escape, didn't you?
狡噛の逃亡をほう助したな
I'm an old man, you know? Cut me some slack.
あんまり老いぼれをいじめんでくれんか
You think that it's okay for Kougami to take the law
into his own hands, as long as evil is defeated as a result.
あんたは狡噛が罪を引っかぶることで
結果として悪がついえると思ってる
That's the savage, selfish idea of "justice"
shared by old-fashioned hunting dogs like yourself.
それがあんたのような時代遅れの猟犬の
野蛮で身勝手な正義感だ
Am I wrong?
違うか
Kougami is the one you're relying on to get the job done.
結局　頼りにしてるのは狡噛だ
You don't expect anything from me.
俺には何も期待してない
You think there's no chance in hell
I can capture Makishima, don't you?
槙島を捕らえられる見込みなんてないと思ってるんだろ
Kougami is a latent criminal as well as an Enforcer.
あの男も潜在犯で執行官
He and I are cut from the same cloth.
俺と同じ穴のむじなだよ
But you're still on a different path than we are.
だが　お前は今でも違う道を歩み続けてる
I truly do think that's for the best. From the bottom of my heart.
それでよかったと心底　俺は思ってる
What kind of justification is that?
よくもそんな奇麗事が言えたもんだ
A culprit runs, and detectives go after him...
犯人が逃げて刑事が追う…
That's what we assumed would happen.
それが私たちの先入観
Inspector?
監視官
But Makishima looks at things differently than we do.
でも槙島の見方は違う
He understands just how much of a bind we're in,
あいつは今私たちがどれだけ窮地に立たされてるか
better than we do ourselves.
私たち以上に理解してる…
Ginoza and Masaoka are in danger!
宜野座さんたちが危ない
Please wait! It's dangerous to go by yourself!
待ってください
１人では危険です
You stay here.
あなたは残って…もし槙島が来ても
If Makishima comes, whatever you do,
don't let him touch the emergency power supply!
絶対に非常電源に触らせちゃ駄目
Destroy the whole console if you need to!
いざとなったらコンソールごと破壊して構わないから
Ginoza! Inspector Ginoza?!
宜野座さん　宜野座監視官
Wait!
待て
Nobuchika!
伸元
Dammit!
くそ…
Hold on!
待ってろ
Behind you!
後ろだ
You bastard!
このーっ
What? Are you trying to blow us both up?
道連れに自爆しようってのか
You think I'd do something stupid like that?
そんなつまらないことをすると思うかい
Don't let that man go! You must stop him at any cost, Enforcer!
絶対にその男を放すな　執行官
You are a detective! Fulfill your duty!
あんたは刑事だ
その務めを果たせ
Pops...!
とっつぁん…
You... You idiot!
バカヤロー
Why did you let the culprit get away?!
何で犯人を逃がした
Why?!
何で…
You're a detective, aren't you?!
あんたはデカだろ
I'm not fit to be called a detective.
デカなんて…
ろくなもんじゃねえよ…
You're my son, after all.
やっぱ親子なんだな
Your eyes... look just the same as mine did...
目元なんざ
若いころの俺に…
when I was your age.
そっくりだ…
Dad...
親父…
Dad!
親父ーっ
Why?!
何でだ
Why?
何で…
It's too late!
遅過ぎるだろうがーっ
So you finally ditched that fake justice
and developed some real bloodlust, huh?
ついにまがい物の正義を捨てて
本物の殺意を手に取ったか
You're everything I hoped you'd be after all.
やはり　君は僕が期待したとおりの男だった
That so?
そうかい
Sorry, but I never had any hopes for you to begin with.
だが　俺は貴様に何の期待もしちゃいない
Don't act so indifferent after coming this far for me.
ここまで来てつれないことを言ってくれるなよ
Cut the arrogance.
いい気になるな
There's nothing exceptional about you.
貴様は特別な人間なんかじゃない
You're just a piece of garbage, forsaken by society.
ただ世の中から無視されてきただけのゴミくずだ
I bet you feel bitter after being rejected by your
peers and excluded from the community, don't you?
たった一人で人の輪を外れて
爪はじきにされてきたのが恨めしいんだろ
You just can't stand to be on your own!
貴様は孤独に耐えられなかっただけだ
You're no different from a kid
whining about not wanting to be left out.
仲間外れは嫌だって泣きわめいてるガキと変わらない
You sure do say some funny things.
面白いことを言うな
Do you think I'm the only one who's left out?
孤独だと？
それは僕に限った話か？
Who isn't alone in this society?
この社会に孤独でない人間など誰がいる
The time when our connection to others was the basis of our selves is long gone.
他者とのつながりが自我の基盤だった時代など
とうの昔に終わっている
There's no place for communities in this world
誰もがシステムに見守られ
where everyone is watched over by the
system and lives within the system's standards.
システムの規範に沿って生きる世界には
人の輪なんて必要ない
Everyone stays in their own little cell,
みんな小さな独房の中で
and the system tames them by giving
them each their own personal serenity.
自分だけの安らぎに飼いならされているだけだ
There's no way I could love anyone,
Dareka wo aisuru koto nante
Dekiru wake nakutte
But I wish to be loved by someone in turn
The world may not have
Dakedo dareka ni aisaretakute
Ended yesterday after all,
Kawaranai kinou ga zutto tsuzuita to shite mo
But we will not budge
Doko ni mo ike ya shinainda
watashi to kimi
From where we are
Kamisama doko he itte shimatta no nee
God, in favor of which parts have you left us?
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
I receive no reply, I never do
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I walk with you
Anata to iku
Donna tsumi mo
I will share all your sins
Seotte ageru
Together with you
Michi naki michi wo
Aruiteku no
I walk
A trackless path
Anata to futari de
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".